人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译  Silmar
翻译  猪猪
翻译 送小孩
翻译 小熊嘟嘟
翻译 潇湘月影
翻译 泰斯
校对  泰斯·雪诺
校对  Silmar
时间轴 加森
时间轴 全家幸福筒
时间轴 imok
时间轴 崽猪
特效/后期 吉吉·波顿
顾问 屈畅(ccxx)
总监 泰斯·雪诺
改编自《冰与火之歌》
原著 乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
第四季 第五集
愿战士赐予他勇气
May the Warrior grant him courage
在危难中护佑他
and protect him in these perilous times.
愿铁匠赐予他力量
May the Smith grant him strength
助他担负重任
that he might bear this heavy burden
愿知晓一切凡人命运的老妪
And may the Crone, she that knows the fate of all men,
为他指明前路
show him the path he must walk
引领他穿越途中的黑暗
and guide him through the dark places that lie ahead.
在七神见证下  我庄严宣告
In the light of the Seven, I now proclaim Tommen
拜拉席恩家族的托曼一世为
of the House Baratheon First of His Name
安达尔人和先民的国王
King of the Andals and the First Men
七国的统治者
and Lord of the Seven Kingdoms.
愿他的统治长久
Long may he reign!
不寻常的一天
Special day.
陛下
Your Grace.
-陛下  -陛下
- Your Grace. - Your Grace.
陛下
Your Grace.
他做到了
There he is.
愿他的统治长久
Long may he reign.
他坐在王座上就像个天生的王者
He sits the throne like he was born to it.
没错  可生来要做国王的并不是他
Yes. He wasn't, though, was he?
的确不是
No, he wasn't.
你还在为乔佛里服丧吗
You still mourn for Joffrey?
他生前是我丈夫  我的国王
He was my husband. My king.
他本会成为你的噩梦
He would have been your nightmare.
陛下  我觉得...
Your Grace, I feel--
你清楚他的本性
You knew exactly what he was.
我也清楚
I did, too.
你永远不会像爱你第一个孩子那样
You never love anything in the world
爱世上任何东西
the way you love your first child.
无论他做了什么
Doesn't matter what they do.
而他所做的事  令我惊骇
And what he did, it shocked me.
你看我是轻易会震惊的人吗
Do you think I'm easily shocked?
不是
No.
他做的那些事  令我惊骇
The things he did shocked me.
他还是个孩子
He's only a boy.
好孩子  乖孩子
A good boy. A decent boy.
一直都是
He always has been.
试问上一位像样的国王是谁
Who was the last decent king, I wonder?
他可能成为五十年来第一位
He could be the first man who sits on that throne
德配此位的贤王
in 50 years to actually deserve it.
那也是一种安慰吧
It would be some consolation, wouldn't it?
相对于将他推上王位的惨事
For all the horror that put him there.
要统治好天下
He will need help...
他还需要帮助
if he's going to rule well.
他有您
He has you.
只有母亲是不够的
A mother is not enough.
我想你仍然有兴趣做王后吧
You're still interested in being queen, I take it?
发生了那么多事...
After all that's happened--
我知道这听起来有些荒唐  可是我...
it sounds strange, I know, but I am--
我还没有想过
I haven't even given any thought to it,
下一步会怎样
what comes next.
这自然是极大的荣耀
It would be a great honor, of course.
但我需要跟父亲商量
But I will have to speak to my father about it.
好  你去找你父亲谈
Yes, speak to your father.
我去跟我父亲讲
I'll speak to mine.
接下来的婚礼会让人应接不暇呢
We may be faced with an alarming number of weddings soon.
到时候我都不知该怎么称呼您
I won't even know what to call you.
嫂子
Sister?
还是母亲
Or Mother?
乔佛里·拜拉席恩国王死了
King Joffrey Baratheon is dead.
在自己的婚礼上被害
Murdered at his own wedding.
我们夺下了弥林的海军  陛下
And we have taken the Meereenese navy, Your Grace.
次子团夺下了弥林的海军
The Second Sons took the Meereenese navy.
谁教你去夺海军
Who told you to take the navy?
没人
No one.
那你为何要去
So why did you do it?
听说您喜欢船
I heard you liked ships.
多少艘船
How many ships?
九十三艘  陛下
93, Your Grace.
可以载多少人
How many men can they carry?
九千三百人  不算水手
9,300, not counting sailors.
这些人足够拿下君临吗
Would that be enough to take King's Landing?
兰尼斯特军队更多
The Lannisters have more.
他们已为乔佛里征战数年
They've been fighting Joffrey's wars for years.
兵士疲敝  军力四散
They're tired, dispersed.
如今又死了国王
And now their king is dead.
八千无垢者  两千次子团
8,000 Unsullied, 2,000 Second Sons
乘船杀进黑水湾
sailing into Blackwater Bay
突袭城门  风卷残云
and storming the gates without warning.
很难说  或许足够
It's hard to say. It could be enough.
但我们打仗不是为了让您当上君临城的女王
But we're not fighting to make you queen of King's Landing.
一万人无法征服维斯特洛
10,000 men can't conquer Westeros.
一旦女王渡过狭海
The old houses will flock to our queen
大贵族会群起拥护
when she crosses the Narrow Sea.
大贵族只会拥护他们认为会取胜的一方
The old houses will flock to whichever side they think will win,
像以往一样
as they always have.
还有别的消息
There's other news.
来自渊凯
From Yunkai.
没有无垢者维护您的秩序
Without the Unsullied to enforce your rule,
贤主们已经重新控制了城市
the Wise Masters have retaken control of the city.
他们再次奴役了留在城里的自由人
They've reenslaved the freedmen who stayed behind
并发誓对您报复
and sworn to take revenge against you.
还有阿斯塔波
And in Astapor,
您留下统治阿斯塔波的议会
the council you installed to rule over the city
被一个名叫克莱昂的屠夫推翻
has been overthrown by a butcher named Cleon
此人已经自立为皇帝
who's declared himself "His Imperial Majesty."
都退下吧
Please leave me.
你留下  乔拉
Not you, Jorah.
看来我解放奴隶湾的成效并不如先前所愿
It appears my liberation of Slaver's Bay isn't going quite as planned.
您可以乘船去维斯特洛
You could sail for Westeros
将这一切抛诸身后
and leave it all behind.
铁王座上的不过是个男孩
A boy sits on the Iron Throne.
据信是个野种  无权继位
A boy many believe to be a bastard with no right to it.
他们从未这般不堪一击
They've never been more vulnerable.
在魁尔斯你曾劝我切勿鲁莽
You counseled me against rashness once in Qarth.
我未听取
I didn't listen.
结果一切顺利
That all worked out well.
我若连奴隶湾都无法掌控
How can I rule seven kingdoms
怎能统治七国
if I can't control Slaver's Bay?
人们凭什么信任我
Why should anyone trust me?
凭什么追随我
Why should anyone follow me?
您是坦格利安传人
You're a Targaryen.
您是龙之母
You're the Mother of Dragons.
我不能止步于此
I need to be more than that.
我不能让获得自由的子民再次被奴役
I will not let those I have freed slide back into chains.
我暂不进攻维斯特洛
I will not sail for Westeros.
那您有何打算
What, then?
我要做女王该做的事
I will do what queens do.
我要统治
I will rule.
罩上兜帽
Pull up your hood.
这样子太显眼
A memorable shade.
他们怎么认得出我
But how would they know?
你知道穷人最喜欢什么内容的故事
You know what kind of stories poor men enjoy the most?
一辈子都见不到的贵族小姐
Ones about rich girls they'll never meet.
这是唯一去鹰巢城的路吗
Is this the only way into the Eyrie?
周围的群山无法逾越
The mountains are impassable.
如果想去鹰巢城
If you want to get to the Eyrie,
血门是必经之地
you need to go through the Bloody Gate.
纵使你有千军万马
It doesn't matter how large your army is,
要想攻打城门  就必须走这条路
if you attack this gate, you do it on this road,
三人并排
three men abreast
然后像羔羊一样被宰掉
and get slaughtered like goats.
最早一批谷地诸侯没什么资源
The first Lords of the Vale didn't have much,
但他们有这片山
but they had these mountains
而且懂得如何加以利用
and they knew how to use them.
他们建造的城堡从未被攻破
And the fortress they built here has never been overcome.
一千年来一次都没有
Not once in 1,000 years.
认清自己的长处  明智地加以利用
Know your strengths, use them wisely,
一人便可对抗千军万马
and one man can be worth 10,000.
待过血门者何人
Who would pass the Bloody Gate?
培提尔·贝里席大人和外甥女阿莲
Lord Petyr Baelish and his niece Alayne.
解除戒备
Stand to.
-解除戒备  -解除戒备
- Stand to! - Stand to!
欢迎回来  贝里席大人
Welcome back, Lord Baelish.
培提尔叔叔
Uncle Petyr!
大人
My Lord.
我给你带了礼物
I have brought you a gift.
贝里席大人
Lord Baelish.
-夫人  -快看培提尔叔叔给我的礼物
- My Lady. - Look what Uncle Petyr brought me.
漂亮礼物配漂亮小子
A beautiful gift for a beautiful boy.
很高兴认识您  艾林夫人
It's a pleasure to make your acquaintance, Lady Arryn.
我叫阿...
My name is Al--
快把兜帽摘下来  孩子
Oh, do take down that hood, child.
我怎么会不认得你
Don't you think I know who you are?
我允准未婚夫离开鹰巢城操办急事
You think I'd let my intended leave the Eyrie on urgent business
怎会不知是什么事
without knowing what that business was?
我放他走  让他把你带来
I let him go so he could bring you here to me.
与我血脉相连的骨肉
My flesh and blood.
能见到您真是太好了  莱莎姨妈
It's wonderful to meet you, Aunt Lysa.
在其他人面前绝对不能这么叫我
You mustn't call me that in front of anyone else.
当然  我明白
Of course. I understand.
不能让人知道你在这儿
No one can know you're here.
否则我们的处境会很危险
It would put us in a very precarious position.
我绝对不说
I would never say a thing.
兰尼斯特想要毁掉我们
The Lannisters want to destroy us.
他们多年来一直在尝试
They've been trying for years.
如今他们尝到甜头了
Now they know what it feels like.
妈咪说他们杀了你母亲
Mummy said they killed your mother
还砍了你哥哥的头
and they chopped off your brother's head.
没错  我父亲也未能幸免
They did, and my father's.
他们也杀了我父亲  下毒
They killed my father, too, with poison.
我本来想让小个子兰尼斯特飞
I wanted to make the little Lannister baby man fly,
但母亲不同意
but Mother said I couldn't.
让他飞
Make him fly?
从月门飞出去
Through the Moon Door.
更过分的是
And on top of everything else,
他们还逼你嫁给那肮脏的怪物
they made you marry that filthy troll.
是的  我们两人都是被逼
They did. They made us both.
提利昂大人也不愿意
Lord Tyrion didn't want to.
这我可不信
I don't believe that for a moment.
他强迫你行房了吗
Did he force himself on you?
没有
No.
-我们没...  -很好
- We never - Good.
罗宾  这是你表姐珊莎
Robin, this is your cousin Sansa.
但除了在我和培提尔叔叔面前
But you're not to call her Sansa in front of anyone
其它场合都不准叫她珊莎  明白吗
but Uncle Petyr and myself. Do you understand?
珊莎  这是我儿子罗宾
Sansa, this is my son Robin.
很高兴见到你  罗宾
It's a pleasure to meet you, Robin.
罗宾  把珊莎带到她房间去
Robin, show Sansa to her chamber.
走后面的楼梯
Take the back stairs.
去吧  过会儿再谈
Go. We'll speak soon.
你怎么去了这么久
What took you so long?
安排国王托曼一世登基
Arranging for the ascension of King Tommen I,
解救珊莎  把她活着带过来
extricating Sansa, getting her here alive.
她来了
She's here.
整个晚上都在处理她的事  还不够吗
We've spent more than enough time on her for one evening.
我们今晚就结婚吧
Let's get married tonight.
难道我们不该
Ought we not...
通知谷地诸侯婚礼的事吗
inform the Lords of the Vale about the ceremony?
谷地只有一个主君
There's only one Lord of the Vale.
其他人都见鬼去吧
The others can all hang.
我丈夫一死  他们就像秃鹰一样
Lurking and simpering on the stairs like buzzards
笑嘻嘻地在楼梯上打埋伏
the moment my husband died,
都想拿爪子抓我
trying to get their claws in me.
我觉得我们可以等到...
I do think that we could wait until--
我不想等了  培提尔
I'm done waiting, Petyr.
我们很多年前就洞房过了
We had our wedding night many years ago.
难道你不记得了
Or don't you remember?
记忆犹新
Like it was yesterday.
哪个妻子可以像我一样为你做那些事
What wife would do for you the things I've done for you?
哪个妻子可以像我这样信任你
What wife would trust you the way I've trusted you?
你给了我那些"泪珠"
When you gave me those drops
要我倒进琼恩的酒里
and told me to pour them into Jon's wine,
我丈夫的酒里
my husband's wine--
你让我写信给凯特
when you told me to write a letter to Cat
告诉她是兰尼斯特...
telling her it was the Lannisters--
此事已过
The deed is done.
烟消云散了
Faded into nothing.
不提起  便没有这回事
Only speaking of it can make it real.
那就今晚成婚
Tonight it is, then.
先容我沐浴更衣
Let me bathe and dress for the occasion.
等我打扮好了  就立刻去叫修士
Once I'm presentable, I'll call on the septon immediately.
事先提醒你
I'm warning you.
我跟丈夫做爱的时候会大声叫出来
I'm going to scream when my husband makes love to me.
那叫声大得
I'm going to scream so loud,
狭海对岸也听得清楚
they'll hear me clear across the Narrow Sea.
你觉得什么时候办婚礼
When will the wedding take place in your mind?
越快越好  只要不失礼节
As soon as decency permits.
给出足够的时间
After we've allowed Tommen
让托曼悼念他的哥哥
the appropriate time to mourn his brother
让玛格丽悼念丈夫
and Margaery to mourn her husband.
-两周后  -应当合适
- A fortnight? - That seems reasonable.
不要杂耍  不要侏儒比武
No jugglers, no jousting dwarves,
不要七十七道菜的大餐
no 77-course meals.
你和洛拉斯的婚礼何时办
And your wedding to Loras?
托曼的婚礼后即刻办
Shortly after Tommen's.
-即刻  -两周后
- Shortly? - A fortnight.
我知道你不喜欢他们
I know you don't like them.
我也不喜欢你的亡夫
I didn't like your husband.
老是拍我的背
Used to pat me on the back a lot.
我不信任他
I didn't trust him.
同感
We had that in common.
与信任之人不必正式结盟
You don't need to make formal alliances with people you trust.
那我们能信任谁
Then whom can we trust?
只有我们自己
Ourselves alone.
提利尔家
The Tyrells
在资源方面
are our only true rivals
是我们唯一的劲敌
in terms of resources
我们需要拉拢他们
and we need them on our side.
劳勃并不是十分富有
Robert wasn't particularly rich.
劳勃有我的资助
Robert had me funding him.
战争就是吞噬金子的无底洞
Wars swallow gold like a pit in the earth.
我想这可以解释上一场战争我们为何大获全胜
I suppose that explains why we did so well in the last one.
你知道过去一年中
Do you know how much gold
西境开采出了多少金子吗
was mined in the Westerlands this past year?
全无头绪
Haven't a clue.
来吧  猜猜看
Go on, your best guess.
以磅  以吨  还是以两计
Pounds, tons, ounces?
无所谓  答案都是一样的
Doesn't matter. The answer is the same.
不可能
That can't be.
我们的最后一座金矿三年前就枯竭了
Our last working mine ran dry three years ago.
那我们是怎么维持开销的
Then how do we pay for anything?
王室欠了布拉佛斯的铁金库
The crown owes the Iron Bank of Braavos
一大笔钱
a tremendous amount of money.
多大
How much?
巨大
A tremendous amount.
您一定能和铁金库的
There must be someone at the Iron Bank
哪个人谈谈  达成什么协议
you can speak to, come to some arrangement.
铁金库就是铁金库
The Iron Bank is the Iron Bank.
没有哪个人一说
There is no someone.
那里肯定有人做事  铁金库由人组成
Someone does work there. It is comprised of people.
神庙由石块垒成
And a temple is comprised of stones.
一块碎了  另一块补上
One stone crumbles and another takes its place.
而神庙屹立千年以上
And the temple holds its form for 1,000 years or more.
铁金库就是这样一座神庙
That's what the Iron Bank is-- a temple.
我们都活在它的阴影中  却几乎无人知晓
We all live in its shadow and almost none of us know it.
你逃不脱他们  骗不倒他们
You can't run from them. You can't cheat them.
无法拿借口敷衍他们
You can't sway them with excuses.
如果你欠他们钱  又不想粉身碎骨
If you owe them money and you don't want to crumble yourself,
那就还钱
you pay it back.
将提利尔家纳入王室
Vesting the Tyrells in the crown
将在这方面给我们极大帮助
will help a great deal in this respect.
这是为了家族利益  我能理解
It's for the good of the family, I understand that.
但两个弟弟未必能
I'm not sure my brothers do.
我知道你想要提利昂无法翻身
I know you're building a strong case against Tyrion.
这是你身为人母的权利
And as a mother, that is your right.
但身为法官  我不能与你谈论审判的事
But as a judge, I cannot discuss the trial with you.
我尊重这一点
I respect that.
我们不用谈
We don't need to discuss it.
兰尼斯特的家业至关重要
The Lannister legacy is the only thing that matters.
您为保护家族不惜发起战争
You've started wars to protect this family.
因为詹姆拒绝
Turned your back on Jaime
为家族的未来效力  您不惜背弃他
for refusing to contribute to its future.
那么将家族的未来
What does Tyrion deserve
付之一炬的提利昂  该遭受何种下场
for lighting that future on fire?
乔佛里
Joffrey.
瑟曦
Cersei.
瓦德·佛雷
Walder Frey.
马林·特兰
Meryn Trant.
泰温·兰尼斯特
Tywin Lannister.
红袍女
The Red Woman.
贝里·唐德利恩
Beric Dondarrion.
密尔的索罗斯
Thoros of Myr.
伊林·派恩
Ilyn Payne.
魔山
The Mountain.
你能闭嘴吗
Would you shut up?
不念完名字我睡不着
I can't sleep until I say the names.
维斯特洛所有人的名字全他妈要念吗
The names of every fucking person in Westeros?
只是我要杀掉的人
Only the ones I'm going to kill.
仇恨是好东西  让人浑身是劲
Hate's as good a thing as any to keep a person going.
好过很多别的东西
Better than most.
如果我们碰到我哥哥
We come across my brother,
也许咱俩的名单上都能划去一个名字了
maybe we can both cross a name off our list.
如果他现在来了  你会怎么做
If he were here right now, what would you do?
我会叫他闭上臭嘴
I'd tell him to shut the fuck up
让我好好睡会儿
so I can get some sleep.
继续  快点念完
Go on, get it over with,
你那份死亡名单
your list of doomed men.
我快念完了
I'm almost done.
只剩一个名字
Only one name left.
念吧
Go on.
猎狗
The Hound.
谢谢
Thank you.
你母亲一直很喜欢吃甜食  你知道吗
Your mother always had a sweet tooth, you know?
-真的吗  -真的
- Really? - Oh, yes.
一到晚餐  她就直接扑向蜂蜜蛋糕
At suppertime, she would go straight for honey cakes,
蜜饯杏仁  奶油蛋羹
candied almonds, custard.
只要是甜的
Anything sweet.
到最后  你外祖父
Eventually, your grandfather
不得不派了个修女监督她吃饭
had to assign a septa to watch her at meals.
毕竟凯特是长女
Cat was the firstborn daughter after all.
她必须保持身材
It was important that she remain desirable
以便钓个金龟婿
so Father could arrange a good match for her
而她开始长胖了
and she was starting to get fat.
我母亲  长胖
My mother fat?
在我吃完正餐前
She never let me have my pudding
她从不让我吃布丁
until I'd finished all my proper food.
那是在她嫁给你父亲  搬到北境之前
This is before she married your father and moved to the North.
到了你出生时
By the time you were born,
她已变得和你父亲一样节俭
your father's austerity had become hers.
婚姻会改变人
Marriage changes people.
我不是要你停下
I didn't mean for you to stop.
吃吧  好好享用
Go on, enjoy them.
味道如何
How do you like them?
非常美味
They're delicious.
柠檬是哪儿来的  这里种不了柠檬
Where did you get the lemons? You can't grow them up here.
当然不是
Oh, gods, no.
培提尔从君临带回了整整三箱
Petyr had three crates brought all the way from King's Landing.
他知道你喜欢柠檬蛋糕
He knew you liked lemon cakes.
他真好
He's so kind.
他非常关心你
He really cares for you.
想想看  要是没有他  你会落到什么境地
Think where you'd be without him.
落在他们手里  接受谋杀罪的审判
In their clutches and tried for murder.
是的  我很幸运
Yes. I'm very lucky.
他觉得有责任保护你
He feels responsible for you.
我知道  也非常感激
Oh, I know he does. I'm so grateful.
为什么呢
Why?
他怎么就觉得有责任保护你呢
Why does he feel responsible for you?
我有一半的徒利家血统
Well, I'm half Tully.
-他这是爱屋及乌  -爱你母亲罢了
- He loved your family so much. - Loved your mother.
-不是  -你就是想说这个
- No. - That's what you wanted to say.
他爱的是您  莱莎姨妈  况且你们成婚了
He loves you, Aunt Lysa. He's married to you.
你母亲从未爱过他  从来没有
Your mother never loved him. Never.
凯特向来只要最甜的
Cat always went straight for the sweetest thing.
最耀眼的  也就是你的伯父布兰登
The most obvious thing. Your Uncle Brandon.
你那傲慢而又残忍的美男子布兰登伯父
Your handsome, arrogant, cruel Uncle Brandon.
差点在决斗中杀了培提尔
He almost killed Petyr in a duel.
但你母亲依然爱他
And your mother loved him anyway.
而现在培提尔不顾生命危险救了你
And now Petyr is risking his life to save you,
救了一个薄情女人的女儿
the daughter of a woman who didn't love him
你母亲对他的情谊还不如他窑子里的妓女
no more than those whores in his brothels.
-他没告诉你吗  -没有
- Has he told you about them? - No.
他没告诉过你  那些女人用身体
He hasn't told you about the vile things
干的脏事儿吗
they do with their bodies?
他在那些女人的身体上干的脏事儿吗
The vile things they let him do with their bodies?
-从来没说过  -你怀孕了没有
- No, never. - Are you pregnant?
什么  没有  提利昂大人和我...
What? No, I told you. Lord Tyrion and I never--
我问的不是提利昂
I wasn't asking about Tyrion.
你有没有让培提尔碰过你
What have you let Petyr do with your body?
-没有  莱莎姨妈  -你这么年轻漂亮
- Aunt Lysa, no, I-- - Your young, pretty body.
-什么都没有  我是处女  -别撒谎
- Nothing. I'm a virgin. - Don't lie to me.
您弄疼我了
You're hurting me.
你瞒不住我
I'll know if you lie.
我发誓  我是处女
I'm a virgin, I swear it.
他爱的是您  莱莎姨妈
He loves you, Aunt Lysa.
他只是说我蠢
All he says is that I'm stupid.
说我是满脑子蠢念头的蠢姑娘
I'm a stupid little girl with stupid dreams
从来不长进  也不会说谎
who never learns and I'm a terrible liar,
所以我什么时候都应该说真话
so I should always tell the truth.
我向您发誓  他从来没碰过我
And I swear to you that he has never touched me.
从来没有  一次都没有
Not once, not ever.
没事了
It's all right.
一切都会好的
It will all be all right.
你很快就会成为寡妇
You'll be a widow soon.
他们马上就要处死那个谋杀国王的侏儒
They'll execute that dwarf for murdering the king
然后你可以嫁给罗宾
and you'll be free to marry Robin.
成为艾林谷的公爵夫人
You'll be the Lady of the Vale.
没人教你怎么骑马吗
Didn't they teach you how to ride a horse?
教过  小姐  那还是小时候
Yes, my lady, when I was young.
但在服侍提利昂大人期间没什么用
There wasn't much call for it with Lord Tyrion, though.
他喜欢坐轿子
He preferred litters.
也许你该留在他身边
Perhaps you should have stayed with him.
这次远行怕是有你好受的
It's not going to be a pleasant journey for you.
看天气好坏  估计要好几周才能到长城
It could take weeks to get to the Wall, depending on the weather.
那是挺远的
That's a long way off.
因为珊莎小姐的哥哥在黑城堡
Well, Lady Sansa's brother's at Castle Black.
换做我  肯定去那里
If I were her, that's where I'd go.
你要是想走  随时都可以
Feel free to stop at any point.
我绝对不走  小姐  我是您的侍从
Never, my lady. I'm your squire.
我没有侍从也一路走过来了
I've made it this far in the world without a squire.
为何这就非要个侍从了
I don't see why I need one now.
骑士都有侍从  小姐
All knights have squires, my lady.
我不是骑士
I'm not a knight.
也不是奴隶主  你不属于我
And I'm not a slaver, either. I don't own you.
我已经宣誓效忠于您  小姐
I swore an oath, my lady.
那我解除你的誓言
I am releasing you from that oath.
也就是说你可以走了
That means you could leave.
我知道
I know.
你觉得你要是走了会怎样
What do you think will happen if you leave?
人们会说我是个不称职的侍从
They'll say I wasn't a very good squire.
你这是干什么
The hell you doing?
练习
Practicing.
-练习怎么死吗  -没人来杀我
- What, ways to die? - No one's going to kill me.
你要是玩这种花拳绣腿  那就等死吧
They will if you nance around like that.
哪有这么打的
That's no way to fight.
这不是打  这是水之舞
It's not fighting. It's water dancing.
舞
Dancing?
那你该穿条花裙子才对
Maybe you ought to put on a dress.
这破烂玩意儿谁教的
Who taught you that shite?
古往今来最伟大的剑士
The greatest swordsman who ever lived.
西利欧·佛瑞尔  布拉佛斯海王的首席剑士
Syrio Forel, the First Sword to the Sealord of Braavos.
布拉佛斯
Braavos.
肯定是个油头粉面的小杂种
Greasy-haired little bastard, I bet.
那儿的人都那样
They all are.
你知道什么呀
What do you know about anything?
那小子的油头肯定比乔佛里的屄抹得还亮
I bet his hair is greasier than Joffrey's cunt.
-那时候可不是  -那时候  他死了吗
- It was not. - Was? He dead?
-是  -怎么死的
- Yes. - How?
-被人杀了  -谁杀的
- He was killed. - Who by?
马林·特兰  所以马林爵士...
Meryn Trant. That's why Ser Meryn--
马林·特兰
Meryn Trant?
古往今来最伟大的剑士
The greatest swordsman who ever lived
居然死在马林·特兰这种小丑手上
killed by Meryn fucking Trant?
-他寡不敌众  -随便哪个小男妓拿把剑
- He was outnumbered. - Any boy whore with a sword
放倒两三个马林·特兰都不成问题
could beat three Meryn Trants.
西利欧没有剑  也没盔甲  只有根木棍
Syrio didn't have a sword. Or armor. Just a stick.
古往今来最伟大的剑士居然连剑都没有
The greatest swordsman who ever lived didn't have a sword?
既然如此  你手上有剑
All right. You have a sword.
看看他都教了你什么
Let's see what he taught you.
来呀  给你那布拉佛斯朋友长长脸
Go on, do it for your Braavosi friend.
他跟你其他朋友一样都死翘翘了
Dead like all the rest of your friends.
你朋友死了  但马林·特兰没死
Your friend's dead and Meryn Trant's not
因为特兰穿了盔甲
'cause Trant had armor
还他妈的有把大剑
and a big fucking sword.
太后陛下
Your Grace.
奥柏恩亲王  在写信吗
Prince Oberyn. Writing letters?
其实是写诗
A poem, actually.
我带你逛逛花园可好
May I show you the gardens?
太后陛下盛情  我岂敢拒绝
I couldn't very well refuse a royal escort.
是啊  没法拒绝
No, you couldn't.
没想到你还是诗人
I didn't realize you were a poet.
蹩脚诗人一个
Not a very good one.
写给情人的吗
For your paramour?
给我的一个女儿
For one of my daughters.
你有好几个女儿吧
You have several, don't you?
八个
Eight.
Eight?
八个女儿
Eight daughters?
五女桀骜难驯
The fifth is difficult.
我给她起了家姐的名字伊莉亚
I named her after my sister Elia.
名字很美
Beautiful name.
是啊
Yes.
可每提起这名字我就觉得悲伤
But I can't say it without turning sad.
悲伤过后
And after I turn sad,
便是愤怒
I grow angry.
也许正因为如此  她才桀骜难驯
Perhaps that's why she's difficult.
诸神就爱开愚蠢的玩笑  不是吗
The gods love their stupid jokes, don't they?
什么样的玩笑
Which joke is that?
你是多恩亲王
You're a prince of Dorne.
大名鼎鼎的战士
A legendary fighter.
威震维斯特洛的大英雄
A brilliant man feared throughout Westeros.
却救不了你姐姐
But you could not save your sister.
我是个兰尼斯特  做了十九年的王后
I'm a Lannister. Queen for 19 years.
父亲是世上最有权势的人
Daughter of the most powerful man alive.
却救不了我儿子
But I could not save my son.
不能保护心爱之人
What good is power
权力又有何用
if you cannot protect the ones you love?
可以为他们复仇
We can avenge them.
是啊  我们可以为他们复仇
Yes, we can avenge them.
你真认为是提利昂杀害了你儿子
You really believe Tyrion murdered your son?
我知道是他做的
I know he did.
等到审判之时  我们便知真相
We will have a trial and we will learn the truth.
是啊  还要审判
We'll have a trial, anyway.
我有一年多没见我女儿了
I haven't seen my daughter in over a year.
我上次见她
The last time I saw her,
她正和我的两个女儿在流水花园游泳
she was swimming with two of my girls in the Water Gardens.
在阳光下欢笑
Laughing in the sun.
我很想相信你的话
I want to believe that.
我想相信她很快乐
I want to believe she's happy.
我向你保证
You have my word.
我们多恩人不伤害小女孩
We don't hurt little girls in Dorne.
世上哪有不伤害小女孩的地方
Everywhere in the world, they hurt little girls.
你能为我带个礼物给她吗
Would you bring her a gift for me?
我没能给她庆祝命名日
I wasn't there for her name day.
也不知道何时能再见到她
I don't know when I'll see her again.
听凭吩咐
Anything at all.
君临手艺最好的造船匠
The best shipwrights in King's Landing
花了几个月造出那艘船
have been working on it for months.
弥赛菈喜欢开阔的水面
Myrcella loves the open water.
我会派人把船驶到阳戟城送给她
I will have it sailed down to Sunspear for her.
请你告诉她
Please tell her...
她母亲非常想念她
her mother misses her very much.
不不不
Oh, no, no, no.
不要  不要
No, no, no, no.
该死
Hells.
天哪
Gods.
你剥皮了吗
Did you remove the skin?
没有  小姐
No, my lady.
你料理过兔子吗
Have you ever cooked a rabbit before?
没有  小姐
No, my lady.
你为提利昂大人做过饭吗
Did you ever cook anything for Lord Tyrion?
没有  小姐
No, my lady.
有厨子做
That was the cooks.
你干什么
What are you doing?
我帮您卸盔甲
I'm helping you with your armor.
我一直都是自己卸
I've been removing my own armor for quite some time,
不劳驾你了
thank you very much.
那你究竟为提利昂大人做什么
What exactly did you do for Lord Tyrion?
我为他端去饭菜
I brought him his meals
他用完餐后再收拾桌子
and cleared his table when he was finished.
我为他换洗衣物和床单
I kept his clothing and linens clean.
为他送信  再带话回来
Carried his messages and returned the replies.
大多数时候都是为他斟酒
Mostly I poured wine.
你跟在提利昂大人身边
Whilst in Lord Tyrion's service,
做过跟战斗有那么一点儿关系的事吗
did you ever do anything remotely related to combat?
我杀过一个人
I killed a man.
谁
Who?
一个御林铁卫
A Kingsguard.
黑水河一役时  他想杀提利昂大人
He tried to kill Lord Tyrion at the Blackwater.
你怎么杀死的御林铁卫
How did you kill a Kingsguard?
我从后面用长矛刺穿了他的脑袋
I pushed a spear through the back of his head.
真该死
Bloody ridiculous.
帮我把这些带子解开
Help me with these straps.
喂
Hey.
喂  起来
Hey, get up.
起来
Get up.
没错  伙计  放到里面
That's it lad, put it inside.
把火生起来  我们冻死了
Get the fire going again. We're all freezing.
是啊  我们需要个姑娘
Aye. What we need is a girl there.
我要撒尿
I've got to have a piss.
安静点
Now keep quiet.
你需要喝水
You need water.
不要紧
It doesn't matter.
当然要紧
Of course it matters.
你不能困在这里
You mustn't let anything stop you.
我已经困在这里了
They already have stopped me.
不
No.
你不在这儿
You're not here.
你离这儿很远
You're far from here.
什么意思
What does that mean?
在山上
At the hill.
有棵巨大的鱼梁木
A great weirwood tree.
你也看到了
You've seen it, too.
我和梅拉  还有阿多
Meera and I, even Hodor,
我们只是来指引你的
we're only here to guide you.
他在等你
He's waiting for you.
我们必须找到它
We have to find it.
你必须到那里去
You have to make it.
我们会的
We will.
这不是结束
This-- this isn't the end.
对你来说不是
Not for you.
还没有结束
Not yet.
我们...
How...
怎么知道什么算结束
will we know the end?
到时候就知道
You'll know.
弟兄们
Brothers.
你脚步的确够轻
You do move quiet.
-几个人  -十一个
- How many? - 11 men.
大部分喝得醉醺醺的
Most of them already drunk.
没人放哨  他们好像什么都不在乎
No guards posted. They don't seem to have a care in the world.
杀他们就如砍瓜切菜
We'll carve them up like walnut pie.
卡尔是跳蚤窝佣金最高的杀手
Karl was a top paid cutthroat in Flea Bottom.
我见过他使刀的手段
I've seen what he can do with a knife.
你见过我使刀的手段吗
Have you seen what I can do with a knife?
还没有
Not yet.
堡垒西面有座小屋
There's a hut on the west side of the keep.
我们应该避开它
We should steer clear of it.
为什么
Why?
里面拴了几只猎狗
They've got some hounds chained up inside.
我们摸得越近越好  只要猎狗闻不到我们
Closer we can get without the dogs sniffing us, the better.
今晚是新月
New moon tonight.
休息一会儿
Get some rest.
日落后行动
We move at sundown.
我向来喜欢卷发的姑娘
I've always liked a girl with curls.
别有风味
A touch of class.
完事了就给你们
You take whatever's left.
拉她起来
Get her up.
住手
Stop.
住手  你要干什么
Stop. What are you doing?
阿多  阿多  阿多
Hodor. Hodor. Hodor.
住手
Stop.
Stop!
-阿多  阿多  -住手
- Hodor. Hodor. - Stop!
-求你了  -阿多
- Please. - Hodor.
-求你了  放开她  -阿多  阿多
- Please, get off her! - Hodor. Hodor.
求你了  求你了  别碰她
Please! Please, leave her alone!
求你了  住手  住手
Please, stop. Stop.
-你干什么  别碰她  -阿多  阿多
- What are you doing? Leave her alone! - Hodor. Hodor.
不要
No!
你的头发真漂亮  不是吗
You've got pretty hair, don't you?
你这么漂亮的贵族家小姐
Now what is a pretty little highborn girl like you
跑到黑乎乎的林子里做什么
doing out here in the deep, dark woods, eh?
不呆在你爹的城堡里  出来自找苦吃吗
You left your daddy's castle looking for trouble, didn't you?
也不打扮打扮
No dresses for you.
你喜欢玩野的  对吧
You like it rough, don't you?
你就喜欢下流肮脏的玩法  对吧
You like it in the gutter, don't you?
如果你放了我姐姐  我就帮你
If you let my sister go, I can help you.
你还能帮我
You can help me?
是的
I can.
你能怎么帮
And how you gonna do that?
我有视野  能看见一些事
I have the sight. I can see things.
很有用嘛
That's very helpful.
看见尚未发生的事
Things that haven't happened yet.
真不错啊
What a fine thing.
真不错
A fine thing.
那你有没有看见我怎么对待你姐姐
Have you seen what I'm gonna do to your sister?
有没有看见他们怎么对待你姐姐
Have you seen what they're going to do to your sister?
没有
No.
别闭眼睛
Don't close your eyes.
我看见你今晚会死
I saw you die tonight.
我看见你的尸体被焚烧
I saw your body burn.
我看见大雪落下  覆盖你的尸骨
I saw the snow fall and bury your bones.
抄家伙
To arms!
他们来了  守夜人
They're here, the Night's Watch.
救援队来了  小子们
Rescue party is here, lads.
小姐
Lady.
-琼恩跟你在一起吗  -是
- Is Jon with you? - Aye.
我带你去见他
I'll take you to him.
你是布兰登·史塔克吗
You're Brandon Stark?
阿多  阿多
Hodor. Hodor.
残废小少爷  我们要骑马上路了  小子
The little crippled lord. We're going for a ride, boy.
琼恩  琼恩
Jon! Jon!
再喊一声  我就割了你朋友的喉咙
Keep talking and I'll cut your friends' throats.
从这个傻子开始  听到没有
Starting with the idiot. Do you hear?
听到没有
Do you hear?
阿多  阿多
Hodor! Hodor!
Hodor. Hodor.
阿多  阿多
阿多  阿多  阿多
Hodor. Hodor. Hodor.
阿多
Hodor.
阿多  把他的刀拿来  给我松绑
Hodor, get his knife. Cut me loose.
阿多  拿他的刀
Hodor, get his knife.
给我松绑  阿多
Cut me loose, Hodor.
还有玖健和梅拉  帮他们松绑
Jojen and Meera, free them.
快去
Go!
琼恩
Jon!
如果他看到你了  肯定不让你往北走
If he sees you, he won't let you go north.
-他是我哥哥  -他要保护你
- He's my brother. - And wants to protect you.
他肯定带你回黑城堡
He'll take you back to Castle Black.
你必须做出选择
You have to decide.
你还想找到三眼乌鸦吗
Do you want to find the three-eyed raven?
-阿多  -阿多
- Hodor. - Hodor.
我们要把夏天救出来
We need to free Summer.
然后就要上路了
And we need to go.
雪诺大人
Lord Snow.
您这是带我回去审判吗
Are you bringing me back for trial?
我们在这儿过得很好
We had a good thing here.
我们有自由
We were free men.
而你永远得不到
You'll never be free.
你永远尝不到自由的滋味儿
You'll never know what that's like.
你在城堡里学过怎么打
You learn how to fight in a castle?
某个老头子教你怎么站位
Some old man teach you how to stand,
怎么格挡  是吧
how to parry?
怎么打得有尊严
How to fight with honor?
你知道尊严这东西有什么问题吗
You know what's wrong with honor?
是你
You.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
跟我来
Come with me.
走
Come on.
我们损失了四个兄弟
We lost four brothers?
是五个
Five.
七层地狱啊  什么怪物能下这么重的手
What the seven hells could do that to a man?
我数了  十个叛徒
I count 10 dead mutineers.
洛克说他们有十一个人
Locke said there were 11 of them.
雷斯特呢
Where's Rast?
-还有一把  -琼恩
- Here's another. - Jon.
我的老天啊
Where in seven hells?
过来
Come here.
我想死你了  小子
I missed you, boy.
拿她们怎么办
What should we do with this lot?
你们留在这里不安全
It's not safe for you here on your own.
曼斯·雷德的大军正朝这边来
Mance Rayder has an army heading this way
还有比曼斯更可怕的
and there's worse out there than Mance.
跟我们回黑城堡
Come with us to Castle Black.
我们给你们找活儿干  保护你们
We can find you work. Keep you safe.
恕我直言  乌鸦老爷
Meaning all respect, Ser Crow,
卡斯特揍我们  虐待我们
Craster beat us and worse.
你的乌鸦兄弟也揍我们  虐待我们
Your brother crows beat us and worse.
我们还是自个儿找活路
We'll find our own way.
你们还要留在
You want to stay here
卡斯特堡垒吗
in Craster's Keep?
全部烧光
Burn it to the ground
和那些死人一起烧掉
and all the dead with it.